Guide to the Whitney M. Young Jr. Memorial Foundation Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Whitney M. Young Jr. Memorial Foundation Records,
1971-1991.
Whitney M. Young, Jr. Memorial Foundation.
38 linear ft. (ca.45,500 items in 92 boxes).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library,
4079908
History
Civil rights organization which created fellowships, scholarships, employment for outstanding members of American minority races, and promoted interracial unity. Sociologist. Whitney Moore Young, Jr. (1921-1971) was Executive Director of the National Urban League, 1961-1971.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, financial records, photographs, memorabilia, and printed materials. The Foundation's correspondence files consist of letters from different organizations and foundations, including the Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Social Change, The NAACP, the United Negro College Fund, the Studio Museum in Harlem, and the YWCA. Also included in this collection are community dialogues on race relations (1974-1975); proposed dialogues (1979) on such subjects as the Boy Scouts of America, Columbia University, and the National Council of Christians and Jews; and files on the Whitney M. Young Fellows Retreat Conferences (1980-1984). The collection contains many files on Ed Wilson's bust of Young (1991), including contracts and agreements, records of payments to Wilson, documents concerning the bust's placement in various locations, correspondence with Wilson (1983-1991), and miscellaneous photographs and pictures. The contributions files contain annual listings of contributions and records of contributions from the National Urban League, assorted organizations, corporations, individuals, foundations, and Phillip Morris.
Also included are files of Margaret B. Young: speeches by Mrs Young, articles, awards, and records of her trips abroad, and public events (UN, UNESCO, Port Authority of New York and New Jersey, Metropolitan Museum of Art). In addition, the collection contains transcriptions of interviews with Dorothy Height, Ann Tanneyhill, and Frankie Adams
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 13 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Foundation Formation and Dissolution
Series III: Chronological Correspondence
Series IV: Board Of Directors
Series V: Legal and Financial Affairs
Series VI: Grants
Series VII: Fellowships
Series VIII: Subject Files
Series IX: Whitney Young, Senior 1976
Series X: Margaret B Young Files
Series XI: Audio and Video Tapes
Series XII: Printed Materials
Series XIII: Oversized Materials
Subjects
Boy Scouts of America.; Columbia University.; Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Nonviolent Social Change.; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.; National Conference of Christians and Jews.; National Urban League.; Philip Morris USA.; Port Authority of New York and New Jersey.; Unesco.; United Nations.; United Negro College Fund.; Studio Museum in Harlem.; Whitney M. Young, Jr. Memorial Library of Social Work.; YWCA.; Adams, Frankie V., 1902-1979.; Bush, George, 1924-; Height, Dorothy I. (Dorothy Irene), 1912-; Tanneyhill, Ann.; Young, Margaret B.; United States--Social conditions.; African Americans--History.; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations.; Charities.; Civil rights.; Libraries--Gifts, legacies.; Sociology, Urban--Societies, etc.; Social problems.; Social service--Societies, etc.; Agreements.; Annual reports.; Articles.; Audio cassettes.; Awards.; Brochures.; Bylaws.; Calendars.; Certificates.; Checkbooks.; Contracts.; Diplomas.; Directories.; Filmographies.; Financial records.; Illustrations.; Interviews.; Invoices.; Ledgers.; Lists.; Memorandums.; Minutes.; Photographs.; Postage stamps.; Posters.; Press releases.; Receipts.; Reports.; Scrapbooks.; Sound recordings.; Speeches.; Transcripts.; Videocassettes.; College teachers.; Endowments--Officials and employees.; Philanthropists.; Sociologists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-98. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1992 M-1992 Archives The Foundation Gift
Gift of the Foundation, 1992.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - George Bush To Margaret Young (Box 1)
  - Whitney Young To Bill Sims (Box 1)
- Series II: Foundation Formation and Dissolution
  - Formation in 1971 (Board of Directors) -- Proposed Fellowship Program -- Bylaws -- Certificate of Incorporation/Correspondence -- IRS Tax Exemption (Box 1)
  - Press Release, August 2, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clipping re formation of Foundation, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Announcement of the start of the Foundation (Box 1)
  - National Urban League Mailing List (Box 1)
  - The Dissolution Files (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re Dissolution (2) (Box 1)
- Series III: Chronological Correspondence
  - Various, 1971 to 1983 (Box 2)
  - Various, 1984 to 1992 (Box 3)
- Series IV: Board Of Directors
  - Guidelines Memos -- Correspondence, misc. -- Address list of board of directors -- 1972 Board establishing guidelines, etc. -- Memos and Correspondence, 1979 to 1985 -- Memos and Correspondence, 1986 to 1992 -- Annual Financial Report to Board of Directors at the Annual Board Meeting, 1971-1972 -- Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Folders for Individual Board Members, Mailing List
    - William Boyd (Box 5)
    - James Breedlove (Box 5)
    - Joseph Cullman (Box 5)
    - Dr. W. Arthur Cullman (Box 5)
    - Alexander Forger (Box 5)
    - Mitchell Ginsburg (Box 5)
    - Charles Hamilton (Box 5)
    - Dr. Barbara J. Holmes (Box 5)
    - Dr. Lindsley F. Kimball (Box 5)
    - James Linen (Box 5)
    - Ersa Poston (Box 5)
    - Hugh Price (Box 5)
    - Leontyne Price (Box 5)
    - Carl Rowan (Box 5)
    - Harvey Russell (Box 5)
    - Frank Saunders (Box 5)
    - Howard Thurman (Box 5)
    - William Trent (Box 5)
    - Daniel Zenkel (Box 5)
    - Lois Zenkel (Box 5)
    - Mailing Lists (Box 5)
    - The Future of the Foundation, Minutes, 5/11/7 to 14/7/81 (Box 6)
    - The Future of the Foundation, Hugh Price, Chairman, 1982 (Box 6)
    - Official Calls for Meetings of the Board, 1971 to 1991 (Box 6)
    - Minutes of 1971 and 1972, Meetings: Organizing, Special Board and Executive Meeting (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 10, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 17, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 17, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 19, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, Sept. 10, 1976 (Box 6)
    - Meeting of the Executive Committee and Selection Committee Minutes, April 19, 1977 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 7, 1978 (Box 6)
    - Minutes Interim Board Meeting, February 21, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 10, 1979 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 8, 1980 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, April 7, 1981 (Box 6)
    - Minutes, 4/16/82 to 4/23/91 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 16, 1982 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 15, 1983 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 12, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Minutes Advisory Committee Meeting re National Urban League Grant, October 25, 1984 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 11, 1985 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 10, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Minutes Executive Committee Meeting, New Rochelle, NY, June 14, 1986 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 2, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Minutes Executive Committee Meeting, September 22, 1987 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 12, 1988 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 18, 1989 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 12, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Minutes, April 23, 1991 (Box 7)
    - Minutes of the Special Meeting of the Board re Grants to be made, October 18, 1990 (Box 7)
    - Annual Review of Progress, 1976 to 1983 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review, 1976 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review, 1977 to 78 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review, 1978 to 79 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review, 1980 to 81 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review (PIPR), 1982 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review of Progress, 1982 to 83 (Box 8)
    - Annual Review of Progress, 1984-1986 (Box 9)
    - Michelle A. Patrick Annual Review of Progress, 1983 to 1984 (Box 9)
    - Annual Review of Progress, 1984 to 85, (Photographs) (Box 9)
    - Lecture, 1984, (Photographs) (Box 9)
    - Michelle Patrick Materials for Annual Review of Progress, 1985 to 86 (Box 9)
    - Memo, 9/2/76 (Box 9)
    - Amsterdam News Newspaper Clipping, 12/21/85 (Box 9)
- Series V: Legal and Financial Affairs
  - Milbank, Tweed, Hadley and McCloy (lawyers) (Box 10)
    [See also: Series 11, Series 1 (Dissolution) and Lucas, Tucker & Co.]
  - Alexander Forger, Jeff Brinck, 1980 to 1992 (Box 10, Folder Folder 1)
  - Special Matters, 1981 to 1982, 84, 87 (Box 10, Folder Folder 2)
  - Milbank's reply to Lucas/Tucker (Box 10)
  - Milbank, Tweed, Hadley and McCloy Invoices for Services Rendered, 1973 to 198- (Box 11)
  - Invoices/Payment, 1975-92 (Box 11)
  - Lucas, Tucker and Co. Audit Materials for years: 1988 to 1991 (Box 11)
  - Lucas, Tucker and Co. Audit Materials for years: 1983 to 1987 (Box 11)
  - Lucas, Tucker and Co. Audit Materials for years: 1977 to 1982 (Box 11)
  - Transmittal of Annual Reports to: Attourney General, IRS, Charities Registration, 1979-1991 (Box 12)
  - Charitable Organizations IRS Annual Reports, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Charitable Organizations IRS Annual Reports, 1973 to 1979 (Box 12)
  - Freedom National Bank Checking Account Correspondence, closed out, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Freedom National Bank Checking Account Statements and Cancelled Checks, 1971 to 19-- (Box 12)
  - Freedom National Bank Foundation Checkbook, 1972 to 1979 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Savings Bank Checking A/C, 1971 to 1978 (Box 13)
  - Financial Information from Various Sources, 1976 to 1978 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Contributions & Deposit Transactions, 1979 - 1980 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Money Market Account, 1990 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Money Market Account, 1985 to 1988 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Money Market Account, 4/21/83 to 1984 (Box 13)
  - Freedom National Bank Passbook, Correspondence, etc. (Box 14)
  - Bowery Savings Bank Passbook, Correspondence, etc. (Box 14)
  - Harlem Savings Bank Passbooks, Correspondence, etc. (Box 14)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account, 1973 to 1979 (Box 14)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account Correspondence, 1976 to 1980 (Box 14)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account, 1981 (Box 14)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Chase Custody Account (Statements/Correspondence), 1982 (Box 14)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account (Statements/Correspondence, U.S. Treasury Bills and Notes), 1983 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account Correspondence, US Treasury Notes and Chase Manhattan Bank Money Market, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account Correspondence, US Treasury Notes and Bonds, Chase Manhattan MM, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank 1986 Custody Account Advices, Statements, Correspondence, US Treasury Notes, Bonds, Money Market, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account (same as 1986), 1987 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account (same), 1988 (Box 15)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody Account Advices, Statements, Correspondence, Money Market, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank US Treasury Notes and Bills (Box 16)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Custody AccountAdvices, Statements, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Chase Special Savings AccountsWhitney Young Fellows, 1980 to 1984 (Box 16)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Check Receipts, 1980 to 1984 (Box 16)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank Checking Accounts, 1980 to 1990, (one folder for each year ) (Box 16)
  - Ledgers Cash Disbursements, 1982 to 1990 (Box 18)
  - Phillip Morris Reimbursements, 1978 to 1983 (Box 18)
  - Foundation Employment/Travel expenses, 1987 to 1990 (Box 18)
  - General Ledgers, 1983 to 1988 (Box 18)
  - General Ledgers, 1989 to 1990 (Box 19)
  - Checks/Invoices, 1979 to 1981 (Box 19)
  - Checks/Invoices, 1982/83 (Box 19)
  - Checks/Invoices, 1984 to 1992 (Box 19)
  - Annual Listings of Contributions as reported to the IRS, 1971 to 1991 (Box 20)
  - Contributions via the National Urban League, 1971 (Box 20)
  - OrganizationsCivic Assn./Churches/Misc. Foundations, 1971 to 198- (Box 20)
  - Corporate Contributions, 1971 to 1980 (Box 20)
  - Ford Motor Company Fund (Box 21)
  - The General Electric Foundation Contributions (Box 21)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Contributions (Box 21)
  - Phillip Morris Contributions, 1972 to 1991 (Box 21)
  - Phillip Morris Matching Funds. Individual Contributions A to G, 1971 to 1991 (Box 21)
  - Individual Contributions H to Q, 1971 to 1991 (Box 22)
  - Individual Contributions R to V, 1971 to 1991 (Box 22)
  - Individual Contributions W to Z, 1971 to 1991 (Box 22)
- Series VI: Grants
  - The Wharton School Endowed Whitney Young Chair, 1992 (Box 23)
    [See also Subject Files: The Wharton School]
  - The Wharton School WMY Memorial Lecture Series Wharton Graduate Division #2, 1981 to 1986 (Box 23)
  - The Wharton School Proposal for MEE Productions T. Fortune, Ivan Juzang, Tama Smith, founders, 1990 (Box 23)
  - The Wharton School Whitney M. Young Jr. Conference (Annual) (Box 23)
  - Memorial House Simpsonville, KY
    - The Lincoln Foundation (WMY Jr. Birthplace), Frankfort, KY (Box 24)
      [See also Subject Files: Memorial House]
    - The Lincoln Foundation Endowment Grant for the Maintenance of Memorial House, 1992 (Box 24)
    - Lincoln Foundation Memorial House (1984 Historic Landmark), Simpsonville, KY, (2 folders ) (Box 24)
    - Materials re Memorial House (Box 24)
  - Whitney Young Magnet High School, Chicago, Ill
    - Magnet School-Funding Sources (Box 25)
    - Printed Materials about the High School including Yearbooks (Box 25)
  - Columbia University-Distinguished Lectureship and Filmography
    - Grant Folder-Whitney Young Distinguished Lectures and Program on Race Relations, 1983 to 1992 (Box 26)
    - Filmography (Box 26)
    - Printed Filmographies (Box 26)
    - Miscellaneous Columbia Grant, (2 folders ) (Box 26)
    - Columbia University Sir Arthur Lewis' speech, 18 November 1985 (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Names of various persons who have been mentioned as lecturers (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Race Relations on Campus (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Proposal: Workshop on Black/Jewish Relations (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Franklin Thomas' Speech of 10/25/84 and news clippings (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Columbia/Greenberg, 1990 (Box 27)
    - Columbia University Lectureship: Expenses/Expenditures (Box 27)
    - Liason Committee Meeting at Columbia (Box 28)
    - Joint Committee Meeting, June 22, 1983 (Box 28)
    - Distinguished Lecture: Mari J. Matsuda, 1991 (Box 28)
    - Distinguished Lecture: Arthur Ashe, 1989 (Box 28)
    - Distinguished Lecture: Charlayne Hunter-Gault, 1988 (Box 28)
    - Inaugural Lecture by Eleanor Holmes Norton (Box 28)
    - Distinguished Lecture Maya Angelou, 1987 (Box 28)
    - Folder for Lectures, 1984/85/87 (Box 28)
  - National Urban League
    - Grant to establish the Whitney Young Leadership Award, 1992 (Box 29)
    - Executive Development and Continuing Education Series, 1986 (Box 29)
    - Leadership Development Program Grant Folder, 1983 to 1985 (Box 29)
    - Minutes and Final Report on the 1984 Exec. Development Program, 10/25/84 (Box 29)
    - Annual Commemoration Ceremony (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box 29)
- Series VII: Fellowships
  - Whitney Young Fellows (Various Proposals) (Box 30)
  - Community Dialogues, 1975 (Box 30)
  - Boy Scouts of America Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Columbia University Alpha Phi Alpha Fraternity Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Fisk University Race Relations Institute, Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Barbara J. Holmes Fellows Proposal, Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - The National Council of Christians and Jews Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Riverside Church Human Relations Dialogue, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Proposed Dialogues, 1979 (Box 30)
  - Retreat Evaluations/Suggestions, 1980 (Box 30)
  - Retreat (Transcripts of Meetings), Tarrytown, (June 20,21, 22 1980 Folder 1 and 2) (Box 30)
  - Retreat, Tarrytown, 1980, (photographs) (Box 30)
  - Community Dialogues, Tarrytown 1980, Survey and other Materials
    - Retreat: Room, Dining Listings, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Retreat: Thank You Letters, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Invitations to Observers, June 1980 (Box 31)
    - Conference Retreat, Tarrytown, 6/20 to 22/80 (Box 31)
    - Allen Morgan Photographer, 1980 (Box 31)
    - Whitney Young Fellows Surveys, 1981 (Box 31)
      [Copy in Individual Files]
    - Association of Fellows Steering Committee contributions listing, 1980 to 1984 (Box 31)
  - Selection Committee and Administration
    - Brochure (Box 32)
    - Mailing List to National Urban League, 1975 (Box 32)
    - Selection Committee Members, 1977 to 1983 (Box 32)
  - Files on Administration
    - Bill Boyd (Box 32)
    - A. Bundles (Box 32)
    - R. Brown (Box 32)
    - J.Chandler (Box 32)
    - S. Cook (Box 32)
    - W.A. Cullman (Box 32)
    - J. Dyer (Box 32)
    - A. Fletcher (Box 32)
    - C. Hamilton (Box 32)
    - B. Holmes (Box 32)
    - Goheen (Box 32)
    - R. Huntley (Box 32)
    - W. Leonard (Box 32)
    - Herman Long (Box 32)
    - E. Poston (Box 32)
    - F. Thomas (Box 32)
    - Cyrus Vance (Box 32)
    - Clifford Wharton (Box 32)
    - C. Willie (Box 32)
    - Fellowship Administration (Box 32)
  - Fellowships
    - Ford Foundation Grants (Box 33)
    - Ford Foundation Grant File (Box 33)
    - National Fellowship Fund (Box 33)
    - Robert R. Moton Memorial Institute (Box 33)
    - Ford Foundation Grants (Box 34)
    - Robert Moton Institute Application/Selection Process (Box 34)
    - Ford Foundation Correspondence re Ford Foundation (Box 34)
    - Fellows Adelona Burgess (Box 35)
    - Adelona, Ebun (Box 35)
    - Beckley, Gemma Douglas (Box 35)
    - Bowens, Faye I. (Box 35)
    - Browning, Jane Smith, (3 folders ) (Box 35)
    - Burgess, Judith (Box 35)
    - Cabell, Cunnigen (Box 35)
    - Cabell, Carolyn, (2 folders and a dissertation ) (Box 35)
    - Carter, Esther (Box 35)
    - Clarke, Hylda T. (Box 35)
    - Cunnigen, Donald (Box 35)
    - Darden, Dorsey (Box 37)
    - Darden, Clifford D. (Box 37)
    - Delgado, Gary (Box 37)
    - Dent, Thomas Covington (Box 37)
    - Dorsey, William (Box 37)
    - (Box 38, Folder Escott, Faulkner)
    - Escott, Paul D. (Box 38)
    - Farrer, Claire R., (3 folders ) (Box 38)
    - Faulkner, Harriet, Y. (Box 38)
    - Faulkner, Gaines (Box 39)
    - Faulkner, Harriet, (2 folders ) (Box 39)
    - Favors, Jo Ann, (3 folders ) (Box 39)
    - Gaines, Lonnetta (Box 39)
    - (Box 40, Folder Gavins, Graham)
    - Gavins, Raymond, (2 folders ) (Box 40)
    - Gebre-Hiwet, Judy T. (Box 40)
    - Godfrey, Frank E. (Box 40)
    - Gonzalez, Alfredo G., (2 folders ) (Box 40)
    - Graham, Debra E. (Box 40)
    - (Box 41, Folder Hall, Hanks)
    - Hall, Robert L. (Box 41)
    - Hamilton, Charles J., Jr. (Box 41)
    - Hamilton, Marmetta (Box 41)
    - Hanks, Lawrence J. (Box 41)
    - (Box 42, Folder Howze Browne, Hayden)
    - Hayden, Wilburn Jr. (Box 42)
    - Henderson, Karla D. (Box 42)
    - Holmes, Barbara J. (Box 42)
    - Howze-Browne, Dorothy C. (Box 42)
    - (Box 43, Folder Howze-Browne, Hudson)
    - Howze-Browne, Dorothy C. Attachment File, Dissertation (Box 43)
    - Hudson, Mildred, (3 folders ) (Box 43)
    - (Box 44, Folder Kappner, Maldonado)
    - Kappner, Augusta Souza (Box 44)
    - Lopez, Iris O., (2 folders ) (Box 44)
    - Lyle, Richard (Box 44)
    - McDonald, Mary F., (2 folders ) (Box 44)
    - Maldonado, David, Jr., (2 folders ) (Box 44)
    - (Box 45, Folder Mann, Murray Gill)
    - Mann, Pamela (Box 45)
    - Mathis, Joyce, (2 folders ) (Box 45)
    - Mayfield, Lorraine (Box 45)
    - Miller, Samuel O. (Box 45)
    - Mori, James (Box 45)
    - Murray Gill, June (Box 45)
    - (Box 46, Folder Pennington, Rivera)
    - Pennington, Gregory, (2 folders ) (Box 46)
    - Pollard, Freeman T., (2 folders ) (Box 46)
    - Richardson, Robert E. (Box 46)
    - Rivera, Reinaldo (Box 46)
    - (Box 47, Folder Sammons, Singleton)
    - Sammons, Jeffrey Thomas (Box 47)
    - Sanchez, Jose Ramon (Box 47)
    - Seck, Essie Tramel, (2 folders ) (Box 47)
    - Silver, Michael (Box 47)
    - Singleton, Theresa A. (Box 47)
    - (Box 48, Folder Speller, Taylor Gibson)
    - Speller, Jeffrey L. (Box 48)
    - Stucker, Jennifer (Box 48)
    - Sullivan, Frances E. (Box 48)
    - Talley Wright, Patricia (Box 48)
    - Taylor-Gibson, Joyce (Box 48)
    - (Box 49, Folder Taylor-Gibson, Thomas)
    - Taylor-Gibson, Joyce (Box 49)
    - Thomas, Augusta E. (Box 49)
    - Thomas, Craig Anthony (Box 49)
    - (Box 50, Folder Trigg, Jones Williams)
    - Trigg-Jones, Yolette (Box 50)
    - Walker, Erin A. (Box 50)
    - West, Emory J. (Box 50)
    - Williams, Adrienne F., (2 folders ) (Box 50)
    - Press Releases and Letters of Contact to Fellows (Box 51)
    - Press releases and photographs, (Folder ) (Box 51)
    - Letters of contact for preparing directories, 1977 to 1992 (Box 51)
    - Chronological, 1978; Jan/Mar 1980 (Box 52)
    - Fellowship/miscellaneous chronological, December 1978 (Box 52)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, 1978-79 (Box 52)
    - Correspondence Sets (Box 52)
    - Sample form letters, 1978/9 (Box 52)
    - Fellowships/Miscellaneous Chronological, Jan-Jun 1979 (Box 52)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, July-December 1979 (Box 52)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, Jan-March 1980 (Box 52)
    - Chronological, April/May 1980-1982 (Box 53, Folder Lonetta Hassell)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, April/May 1980 (Box 53)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, June/August 1980 (Box 53)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, September 1980 (Box 53)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, Jan-March 1982 (Box 53)
    - Lonetta Hassell Chronological, April to end of 1982 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous fellowship materials (re. mailing list, directory, and applications) (Box 54)
    - Nominator Mailing Lists and Inquiries, 1977 to 1984 (Box 54)
    - Application forms and correspondence materials, 1982 to 1983 (Box 54)
    - Application revisions (Box 54)
    - Application Material, 1977/78 (Box 54)
    - Application Material, 1978/79 (Box 54)
    - Information for the directory (Box 54)
    - Memo re directory (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous materials re fellows (Box 54)
    - Miscellaneous Fellowship Materials re Selection Committee (Box 55)
    - Selection Committee, 1979 (Box 55)
    - Selection Committee, 1980 (Box 55)
    - Selection Committee, 1982 (Box 55)
    - Requests for assistance, 1987 (Box 55)
    - Administration of other fellowship programs (Box 55)
    - Printed Materials: "Selected List of Post Secondary Education Opportunities for Minorities and Women,", 1979 and 1980 (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous fellowship information (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous fellowships re Hispanic fellows (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous Materials and Photographs re Fellows (Box 55)
    - Miscellaneous Fellowship Materials (Box 56)
    - Financial Assistance Info (Box 56)
    - Data Information, 1983/84 (Box 56)
    - Other Fellows/Awards Programs (Box 56)
    - Appeals for foundation support (Box 56)
    - General listing of Financial Aid Sources, (2 folders ) (Box 56)
    - Appeals for Financial Aid (Box 56)
- Series VIII: Subject Files
  - University of Illinois (Box 57)
  - U.S. Department of Education National Advisory Committee on Black Higher Education and Black Colleges and Universities, (3 folders Report) (Box 57)
  - Burger King WMY Black History Advertisement (Box 57)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1991 (Box 57)
  - Ralph J. Bunche Memorial Project (Box 57)